Gerald had been
diagnosed with prostate cancer.
Something that Kaleb
and I discussed
while trying to do what our
absent friend normally does.
Bollocks.
No.
It's
bloody complicated.
Yeah.
I've been phoning
round doctors and things I know.
Yeah?
And his
odds are really good.
- But it's scaring him to death.
- Yeah.
He doesn't understand.
No. I know he doesn't
understand. And he's bewildered.
Because. for obvious reasons.
somebody said: "Sorry. it's cancer."
- That's all he heard.
- Yeah.
He's desperately upset.
Terrified. poor man.
No.
He's a strong man. He's
worked the land all of his life.
He's not unfit. is he?
He can do a day's work at...
- What age is he?
- 74.
He's amazing.
We were now
heading into late autumn.
And on Kaleb's side of the farm.
in one of the arable fields.
things were not going well.
So. Jeremy and Charlie said it was
too late to plant oilseed rape.
I took the decision. as farm
manager now. to plant it myself.
And unfortunately. it's failed.
Fucking annoying.
And when Kaleb
came over to see me.
he became even more annoyed.
Who the fuck is that?
It's interesting
you should ask that.
because it's actually
half of Groove Armada.
Who?
Half of... He was
in Groove Armada.
I don't know what that is.
Why is he drilling my field?
Er...
The thing is that
fellow Doncaster-boy Andy Cato
no longer does
this for a living.
Like me. he's now
moved into farming.
And a couple of weeks earlier. he and
his business partner. George Lamb.
had dropped round to talk
about their big idea.
- I know it's called regenerative farming.
- Yeah.
But I'd really like to
understand what it is.
Our current farming system
declares war on natural systems.
And tt's got us
in a bit of a fix.
Our soils have been
pounded and poisoned
to a point where they're within
a few decades of giving up.
We've lost 80% of our insects.
so we can't keep doing that.
Regenerative farming is a way of farming
which tries to copy natural systems.
- But it's not organic?
- No.
In organic. the main thing
is about not using
any chemicals.
Where we're different is we're
about assessing each bit of farmland
and trying to figure
out what it needs.
So if we took the plant and
we took a reading from it.
and it told us that
you were missing boron.
or magnesium or
something specific.
we can feed according to need.
rather than going and just dumping
thousands of kilos onto the field.
That's what we do.
We filled a sprayer up with
gallons and gallons of chemicals
and just go out
and do every field.
Andy then explained that
the goal with regenerative farming
was to copy the way nature
likes to mix things up.
One thing you'll never find in
the woods or along a hedgerow
or any natural system.
is one type of plant.
Nature never allows one type
of plant to grow in a big area.
If you look in a drought
year like this year.
all the bits that stood up to it
are the hedgerows. the woodlands and
the bits that we haven't touched.
The bits that have stayed green?
Yeah. And the thing is.
as the hedgerow or the woodland
or the meadowland prove.
when that's working.
you don't need to put anything
on it. Nature's got it sorted.
So what we've got to get
away from is monocultures.
You're suggesting planting
wheat and something else
- in the same field at the same time?
- Yeah.
So the idea of wheat and beans
is a good starting point.
- In the same field?
- Yes.
Two things are happening there.
One is that the nitrogen
from the atmosphere.
of which there's an
infinite abundance
80% of it. isn't it?
The beans are taking that down
and putting it in the soil.
- to replace fertiliser inputs.
- The beans are?
- The beans are.
- They're great nitrogen fixers.
And so. by putting two
plant families in the same field.
we're starting that process
of feeding the soil microbes.
which we need to help recover
with a diversity of plants.
Your yields are
going to be way down.
You're not going to grow as many
beans as if you just had a bean field
or as much wheat. surely?
Here's the thing.
The overall output
will be higher.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I know what you mean.
- Net-margin-wise. at the bottom line.
- Yes.
Overall you might do less
yield in actual weight with us.
But if you take all
those input costs out.
for example. the chemical prices
are going up and up and up
our margin is higher.
Plus. you're also building
health into your soil
so you can farm indefinitely.
If you carry on using the same
extractive system based on chemicals.
the likelihood is in a
couple of generations' time.
you won't be able to
produce food on your farm.
So if we started to think
not in terms of yield.
like the weight we get out of a
field. but in how much money...
We only ever talk about.
"We got so many
tonnes per acre."
If we start to talk about
how many pounds per acre...
Yeah.
I like
the sound of this.
Yeah. because you're not
having to give Mr CF Industries
£1.000 for your fertiliser.
Exactly.
Then came the
really enticing bit.
Andy and George would guarantee
to buy any crops we
grew using their method
for a premium price.
You buy it?
- We buy it off you at a premium.
- That's even better.
You buy for more than I would get
from an ordinary grain merchant?
Yeah. For sure.
Who do you sell it to?
We're at about 250
regular customers.
and that spreads from
small artisan bakeries
to Marks & Spencers.
- Marks & Spencers?
Marks & Spencers.
So your flour that you sell
us can be going into M&S.
Charlie
and I were sold.
So I'd handed over one
of the fields to Andy...
To see if his new soil-friendly
system would work.
And now. I just had to hope
that Kaleb wouldn't mind.
That's pissing me off
seeing him in there.
You don't know what he's
drilling yet. wheat and beans.
I see a bean bag.
Yeah. he's got wheat
and beans in his hopper.
It's my field. though.
I've drilled this field
for the last 6 years now.
You won't have to this
year because he's doing it.
He's putting it in
with a disc drill.
- That's not gonna work.
- Why not?
Look out there. What do you see?
- Mud.
- No. The other thing with the mud.
- Stones.
- Yes.
Do you know how a
disc drill works?
We've got a tine drill for that
reason. It moves the stone out the way
then plants the seed.
- Yeah.
- Yes?
You put a disc drill through
that. that'll go over the stone
and plant the seed
on top of the stone.
- Will it?
- Yes.
Hmm...
He's probably on Boy's
Land. This is Man's Land.
I then put on
my "Boutros Boutros" hat.
because it was time for
the two of them to meet.
Be nice. Don't be
petulant like a child.
Andy. Kaleb.
- How you doing?
- Kaleb. Andy.
- He's thrilled.
- Nice to meet you.
- Looking pretty thrilled. yeah.
- No. Oh. here's somebody else.
- Hi.
- Been planting with a trowel?
- Scratching like a chicken.
Yeah.
The first thing he
says is you're using
a disc drill. which
won't work in that field.
- Yeah?
- There's a lot of stone.
There are?
- Do you think it'll work?
- I'm with you with the stones.
This drill is set up to sow
two things at the same time
and put a bit of probiotic
liquid down with the seed.
If we get through the stones.
we can get the job done.
What's the liquid
for? Fertiliser?
No. it's like. er...
We're gonna try and bring
the soil back to life.
- And get all the things...
- It is alive.
If I farm that bit there and
you rip this bit up and put your
whatever you're doing. in here.
you'll get a better yield?
No. no. no.
Okay. Would you make
more money than I would?
Well. let's go back
a step. because if...
- You're tall as the sun.
- What's that?
- If...
- My neck.
Do you want me to come
down the down slope?
Yeah. if
that's all right.
- Yeah. better.
- That's better!
What are
you planting? Wheat?
- And beans.
- How do you harvest it
and not lose anything
out the back?
You set it so you're not
losing anything out the back.
- It'll go through a grain cleaner.
- Which costs more money.
You don't have to take care of
that because part of the deal is
that we'll just take the wheat and beans
together and we'll sort it all out.
- They do that.
- Do we sell it to you then?
Yeah.
- And they pay a premium.
- Fine.
Next question.
then. Was you in a band?
- I was.
- I can tell.
Because?
Because you've left your tractor
running at a pound a litre.
It was
now late November.
And I had my head buried
in my latest homework.
Yorkshire pig.
Who are you looking at?
Because despite Charlie's
protests. I'd bought some pigs
and their arrival
was only days away.
Corrugated iron.
As a result.
I had to get three big pens
built in the potato field.
This would be a lot of work and
I really needed some expert help.
Kaleb is ill.
Okay.
First rule. you would have thought
with farming. you go to work. The end.
There is a really bad
cold going around.
- Yeah. but it's a cold!
- It's horrible.
Foetuses. Honestly.
Could you grab the telehandler?
Since it's an emergency.
Look at this!
This is the Diddly Squat
Heavy Machinery Unit
swinging into action here.
Whoa.
Bloody hell.
Wind!
No! I've got my own sail!
- You know what pigs I'm getting?
- No.
They're called
Shandy and Blacks.
- Ooh!
- And they are from...
- See the forest over there?
- Yeah?
That's where they're
from. Forest of Wychwood.
- You are kidding?
- No.
- A few years ago...
- Uh-huh?
There was only one
man pig left.
- Boar?
- Yeah. One left in the whole world.
- No way?
- And it was rescued by a farm in Dean.
They're bringing it back. So I've
decided to get Shandy and Blacks.
It sounds like a sort of thing a
northern woman would drink in a pub.
- 83 m?
- There.
- This is the other corner.
- Here we go.
Look. a farmer! At work!
Possibly with a
light cold. mild flu.
but able to go to work.
Having measured out the pens.
our next job was to install the fences
using a post knocker I'd
nicked from Kaleb's yard.
Right.
- What we need to do is get that pin...
- In the middle.
- Into there.
- Okay.
Oh. wow!
- Are we happy?
- Yep.
Oh nice.
Can you imagine putting someone's
head there? 'Oomph! Gone.
- "Gangs of London."
- This would be a great one.
We should do "Gangs of Chipping Norton"!
Put people's heads on this!
- Shall I put these every 3 metres?
- Yeah.
It really is raining
now and officially night.
- I've done the maths.
- Yep.
And we're gonna have to
put in 75 fence posts
before we start putting
the actual fencing up.
We're not quick.
but it is our first day.
- Yep.
- And we can be proud of ourselves.
Right. we've gotta
thread this through here. Yeah.
Ooh. that was juicy.
Right. now. here we go.
When I drive forwards.
it's going to tension it.
No. no. no. no. no. no!
Jeremy? Whoa. whoa!
You've pulled it over.
What? Pulled what?
I was screaming at
you and you can't hear.
- What have I pulled over?
- You pulled the last post over.
Eejit.
Fucking ripped the
whole thing up.
You're meant
to be looking at me.
- We could have used the phone.
- We can all blame each other.
No. it's not that.
I was trying to make sure that the
thing wasn't wobbling at the front.
"Blame each other"?
We're gonna have to put the
post... How are we gonna...
Wait. This is more of a problem.
No. stop just for a second.
The corner post has to go
there to be in line with that
- and in line with this.
- Uh-huh.
And we've loosened the
ground up. haven't we?
We hav... "We" have?
Yeah. "we" have.
When the
fences were all up.
we quickly discovered we'd
given ourselves a problem.
Hang on. Let's
think about this.
If you open that one...
Yep.
Right. So we have to
open this one first.
Or we have to take
this one off. Do we?
Well. if we open
this one first...
- No. it's...
- We fucked up.
- I know we did. It should've been...
- So take that off.
Yes. Exactly.
Despite the setbacks. though.
we managed without Kaleb or Charlie
to finish the pens.
And then. we had to start
work on the pig houses.
which came with my
least favourite thing:
An instruction manual.
From this to this in 30...? Fuck
off! 30 minutes my arse. Look!
- That goes on there like that. yeah?
- Oh. yeah? Okay.
It's IKEA. but for pigs.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Is that on the...
where it's painted?
- Okay.
- Perfect.
Er...
- Oh for fuck's sake!
- What?
There's no door.
- We were supposed to use that.
- Oh those go there.
Jesus.
Okay?
I picked up the nearest bit of wood.
I didn't realise you needed a door.
But pigs need doors.
We've gotta swivel it
round. haven't we? Yeah.
We've now been
exactly half an hour.
Right.
Sansa? Arya?
Oh! I'm going backwards.
Sansa! Arya! Come here.
Sansa? Arya? Dogs?
Oh. they're here.
Sit.
Arya. sit.
Oh. God.
Right. look. well.
it's firm... ish.
That's good. Let's
get the next one.
I can't remember how
many days it's taken us
to build this pig
migration centre.
but we have pretty much done it.
Yep.
Perfect.
I am actually feeling
really rather pleased with that.
If there's any pig farmers
watching who wanna write in. do.
Mark your envelope: "Yeah.
we were impressed as well."
Er...
"Diddly Squat Farm. Chipping
Norton. Oxfordshire."
But. despite
our best efforts.
the pig hotel wasn't
quite finished
by the time our guests arrived.
- I'm Jeremy.
- Hello. Jeremy.
How are you? This
is Lisa. Wherever she is.
- Hello. there. How are you?
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Hi. I'm Peter.
- Hi. Josh. Nice to meet you.
- Hello. Josh. How are you?
- What have you got here?
- Proper pig boards.
What are they for?
To steer the pigs in the
paddocks. so they don't run that way.
- Oh. you use the board. I see.
- Oh. right. Easy.
You can't put them on a lead.
I've seen Babe! I
know how it works.
Piggies!
- How old are these ones?
- About a year.
Are they what you call
weaners? Or are they gilts?
Moving on from
weaners to gilts. yeah.
I can't wait to get
them. Can we get them out?
Yeah.
Here they come!
Good pigs.
Oh. they are
fantastic! Look at them!
You rare breed. you!
- So those are how old?
- They're coming up to a year now.
I love their
socks they've got on.
I know!
But there's one...
Oh. bigger pig.
Much bigger pig coming.
- Why is this one so much bigger?
- She's much older.
- How old is she?
- This is a breeding sow.
About two. So she has had baby.
They haven't met before.
- Oh. haven't they?
- No. So there might be a little
of working who's who.
I'll keep these back.
shall I? Come on.
- And they're all lady pigs?
- All lady pigs.
They've got their hackles up
on the back of their neck.
Like a dog?
That's how you know they're
getting a bit grouchy with each other.
And they just don't like
each other because...?
They've not met before.
They'll make friends soon.
- Fight! Fight! Fight!
- Girls. be nice.
This is a proper...
She's much bigger.
but they've got each other.
so they'll stand their ground.
Shall we get the electric gates
on? There you go. You're on now.
We're on. So if
they touch it now...
- There you go.
- It's working.
- The electric fence is on.
- Yeah.
It was then time to put
the young piglets in their compound.
- Ten in here for you.
- I'm looking forward to this.
Come on. piggies.
Welcome to Diddly Squat.
- They're gorgeous.
- Aren't they fantastic?
Yeah. they're glorious.
Piggly Squat. That's
what the herd's called.
It is a superb breed.
When the sun shines
on them. they look metallic.
Chestnut.
They're like conkers.
Nobody here will
remember the NSU Ro 80.
There was a car
called the NSU Ro 80.
You used to be able to get that
in exactly the same colour.
- Really?
- A sort of metallic bronze.
Yeah.
- He's found the potatoes. look.
- Yeah.
They're gorgeous. Look at
them running around. They like it.
Oh!
Lisa's
beside herself!
You're so cute!
Aren't
they just the best?
Yeah!
"It's potatoes! Potatoes!"
Look at them!
They've gone mental!
"Oh. this is lunch! It's literally
lunch everywhere you look!"
They all follow each
other. Oh my God. they're so cute.
That one
thinks it's a dog.
What are you doing down there?
So how long are they
here for? A couple of months?
Yeah. They
winter up here.
Hey. girlies.
Till they've
eaten all the potatoes.
- And then they're off.
- Oh! The Piggly Squats!
Finally. we had to
release the last group of pigs
into the pen where...
sex would take place.
So this for the middle field
is a sow. a gilt and a boar.
- So sows had babies before?
- Yeah.
- A gilt...
- A gilt hasn't.
This is Mabel.
She can be a bit cheeky.
- And Mabel is a sow?
- Yes.
Come on. Sarah.
Come on. Sarah!
Come on.
darling. Come. pig.
I do know the
boar is called Ajax.
- Ajax?
- Ajax.
Here we go.
- He's a young boar.
- Yeah. he is.
He's nowhere near as stocky
as I thought he'd be.
He's young. though.
- Here he goes. Look.
- Here we go.
Hello. Look at this.
This is the meeting of...
- "Hello. sailor."
- Sarah and Ajax.
Love at first sight.
Aw. they're kissing.
There was. however. no time
to enjoy this Mills & Boon moment.
Because we had to get the
throuple's pig house built
before nightfall.
Here comes your house.
Ajax and Sarah and Mabel.
So if there's a big "clonk".
I could squidge a pig.
That's good.
It is now
dark.
Okay.
Oh-oh.
The sow is now going to
join Lisa.
There you go. See?
Oh. no! More
worryingly. here comes the boar.
- That is...
- Oh. no. no. no. Not all of you!
Jeremy?
Erm... Jesus.
♪ I'm sorry for the
things that I told you ♪
♪ But words only go so far ♪
♪ And if I had my way I
would reach into Heaven... ♪
The Piggly
Squat pigs settled down
to the business of settling in.
♪ And pearls from a summer sea ♪
♪ But all I can give you
is a kiss in the morning ♪
♪ And a sweet apology ♪
♪ And tomorrow's gonna
be a brighter day ♪
I. meanwhile.
cracked on with farming life.
which. this week. included one of
Charlie's skull-numbing catch-ups.
If we were to plant woodland.
there is the Woodland Carbon Code.
So. the long and
the short of it is
we could put those
into a herbal ley.
We have to tell
Defra we're keen.
We need to make that
application by the end of March.
allocated a certain
percentage of their income
to environmental. social
and ESG governance.
You know. particularly the
food industry. Scope 3...
And. after I
woke up two days later.
I had to send the precious
spelt wheat off to the mill.
Right. I'll just load
this grain lorry by myself
because Kaleb is still
being a Millennial.
Here we go.
Can we edit this out?
A week after the pigs
arrived. I took Lisa to see them.
because my breeding
plans had hit a snag.
So the big
problem I've got is
whenever you see the
boar mounting that sow...
Uh-huh?
How can I put this
delicately? He can't reach.
Do you have
to give him a hand?
Well. he's much smaller
- than she is.
- Yeah.
- So when he gets on her back.
- His penis...
- Yeah.
Isn't long enough to
get into her vagina.
Er. well.
I'm sure she's...
There's a way of working
that out. isn't there?
Hello. pigs.
Luckily. we
arrived just in time
to see the little boar
having yet another attempt
to mount the much bigger sow.
There he goes.
But this is the problem. look.
Look how much smaller he is.
He's too small.
It's not going in.
Go on. get it in. It's not in.
It's not in. you
blithering idiot.
It's not coming
out either. to be honest.
His cock's come off.
Where's it gone? His
cock's not coming out.
Come on!
Er...
I don't know what
you do about this.
She's being very patient.
Well. she's desperate.
But you're gonna have to
move your feet forwards.
That was just the most
terrible shagging ever.
- He's desperate.
- He just pushed her.
Oh no. you've electrocuted her.
Aw. Look.
he's saying sorry.
We decided to leave him
in the sex pen for another week.
in the hope he'd get the
birds and the bees sorted out.
This meant we could
focus on other things.
which was handy.
Because a couple
of days later...
Jeremy. a farmer down the road.
brought some old friends back.
There you go.
Look who it is!
Hello. "sheeps"!
A moment
only slightly spoiled
by a social faux pas.
Hello.
Jeremy the Younger.
- Hi. Lisa. How are you?
- Good.
- Congratulations on your marriage.
- Thank you.
I didn't know.
Yes. we're invited to
the wedding. darling.
- I did know. How's it going?
- Yes.
Then it was
time to prep the barn
where our remaining cows would
be living through the winter.
Another job where Kaleb was
conspicuous by his absence.
- You know he's better? Fully recovered.
- Yeah.
So much better he's
gone on holiday.
- You're joking? How long?
- All week.
- What?
- He's gone to Cornwall.
He'll get a nose bleed. because it's
more than a mile from Chipping Norton.
But he's gone. In this weather.
- I suppose he thinks...
- Yeah?
His side of the
farm. the arable side.
he can't do anything. so he
may as well be on holiday.
- I thought he was farm manager?
- Our side of the farm.
the profitable side of the farm.
we have to put in a shift.
How did the world work
without telehandlers?
I do not know.
Yeah. forward.
Yes!
Come on. cows.
Hiya. Gently. Hiya.
Look. Your hotel!
- Hiya. Hiya.
- Go on.
No. Uh-uh. uh-uh.
That's the
one. That's the one.
Oh. man. Yeah!
I'll let you
out in five months.
Look at that. Mr Cow.
Okay. We're done.
A pretty idyllic
sight. that is. Look at that.
You
look delicious.
We had to assume.
while all this was going on.
that the boar had done
his thing in the sex pen
and that we could now introduce him
to the ladies in the next pen along.
Hello. pigbies.
This turned out to be one of
the wettest and most confusing hours
of my entire life.
Oh. here comes the
rain again. Now...
Okay. Annie Lennox.
Oh shit. This is like
Tetris. Where does this go?
- Oh it's really raining.
- Okay.
Yeah.
This is heavy rain now.
- Quickly do it.
- Oh. nearly. Keep going.
- Yes!
- Yes! Well done. Lisa.
Well done you.
Ow!
- It's attached somehow to the electrics.
- You gotta...
Can you stop
the pigs coming out?
It's just a clearing-up shower.
That doesn't work.
You're dead right.
You have to...
We didn't measure
it properly. did we?
No. we
didn't. "We" didn't.
Okay. quickly.
open that one.
Open that one.
And I'll somehow
get the boar without the...
Now. we only need
the one with the penis.
Oh! Okay.
- Not her.
- There you go. Look. Biscuits!
Oh shit! No! Fuck!
- Where's that one come from?
- What?
- One of the gilts got in.
- Oh shit.
- Which was which now?
- Which one was it?
Er...
This one?
Yeah. this one.
The little ginger.
Well. we've
gotta get that back.
Oh. Christ. I
fucking hate farming!
Come on.
No. no. stop it.
Stop it.
Go. No. stop.
You. stop. Stop. Stop.
As I tried to
grab the young filly.
the older lady pig got cross that
her boyfriend was suddenly interested
in a slimmer alternative.
No. no. stop it.
She's jealous.
He's going to pork her.
He's on already.
But the big sow wants
to be porked. Look.
Look. if I pretend to
be shagging her here.
she's gonna leave
that one alone. right?
Yes. but we've got to
keep this one... No.
Look. look. look. She's jealous.
The only solution
was to distract the older sow
with something better than sex.
- Have a ginger nut biscuit.
- No. she...
- Look at this.
- She doesn't know it's not the boar now.
You see?
I'm trying to spot if his
cock... Yes. his cock's out!
- Okay.
- His cock's out!
- And in. It's in.
- She doesn't know...
No. let him finish.
- That I'm not...
- No. let him just finish.
Get the biscuits.
darling. Get the biscuits!
- But which one for?
- For this one.
Look. she's fascinated
by the whole thing.
No. don't put your
face in it. Oh. God.
Here. have a biscuit.
Oh God.
It's the
longest... Come on. man.
Jeremy. I think you
should be doing this bit.
Has he
not finished yet?
Jeremy. can you do
on the back of her. please?
And I'll do the biscuits.
Come here.
Right. She's got to think
that she's having sex.
And I'm now giving her that
impression. according to my book.
Oh. but she's having a biscuit
and sex simultaneously.
And she prefers biscuits.
- Here. biscuits. biscuits.
- Will you hurry up?
Honestly.
You're having sex.
Lovely. romantic.
it's Barry White.
No. don't! Lisa. just
pay attention to the pig!
- You're going to interrupt-
- Biscuits. biscuits.
Don't pull it out.
He must finish in a minute.
Oh. he has!
Huge quantities of sperm.
No. no. no.
Back it goes.
The porkscrew is away.
Okay. quickly.
Eventually. we
got all the pigs sexed
and back to where they
were supposed to be.
And I could relax.
Oh shit.
What the hell?
What the hell is that?
Has one of the pigs
been sick in my pocket?
You're kidding?
- Look.
- What the...?
What the
bloody hell's that?
- Is that? Is it?
- Ugh.
Ugh.
For fuck's sake.
It was now
almost two months
since the other Donny boy had planted
his wheat and beans in the field.
And Charlie reckoned
we should check up
on how his regenerative
farming was going.
So can I just ask. Charlie?
All the stuff that looks like grass...
- Yeah.
- Isn't grass? That's wheat?
Yeah. That's
wheat. And then these here.
they're beans.
- Were beans.
- Look. I picked up the roots.
That's quite exciting.
And this is what
Kaleb said won't work...
He said the
drill wouldn't work.
- Well. it has.
- Correct.
- That's bloody good. isn't it?
- Yeah.
Who knew? Old Groove Armada's
done a good job in here.
Well. it looks okay.
And then...
Look. there's no
disease. They're clean.
Look at all those worms. Jeremy!
That's what he'll get excited about.
- Who? He will?
- Yeah. Earthworms.
Do you
know what this shows?
It shows that you've
uprooted a perfectly healthy plant.
- thus depriving me of some cash.
- There's some nodules on there.
Since we're here. we might as
well have a biology lesson.
There's some nodules on here.
And that's the bit that the
magic happens in the legume
where it makes nitrogen
from the atmosphere
and stores it in the plant.
- That's what we're trying to do?
- Yes.
But back in the soil. isn't it?
Well. this won't release the soil
till we kill it and destroy it.
But they've gone pink. See
how it's fleshy pink in there?
- Yeah.
- Which means they're active.
The bacteria in
your soil are making nitrogen.
A man from Groove Armada is
making nitrogen in my soil.
Nobody's ever said that before.
It's never been
used as a sentence.
Charlie and I
then headed to the office
to discuss the council's
enforcement notice.
Which didn't just shut
down the restaurant.
It made running the farm shop
nigh on impossible as well.
They wanted us to
close the small bar
where customers could
buy my Hawkstone beer.
They didn't want us
parking cars in the fields.
And said the loos had to go.
And worst of all. they were
insisting we shut the burger van.
Check on one burger.
two truffle. one chilli.
Thank you very much.
Which was now the only
realistic way of selling our meat.
Thank you
very much. Thank you.
The restaurant. I could
never see that coming back.
but we had to do something
to protect our shop.
- Farm shop.
- We've got some choices to make.
- Okay.
If they make that
enforcement notice stick.
"no car parking".
they'll ban parking on the road.
and we won't be able to sell
anything other than an apple.
So I was thinking. why don't
we try and move the farm shop
up here?
That's out of Chadlington's
parish council area.
And more importantly. this bit
isn't in the Area of
Outstanding Natural Beauty.
- No.
- So what if we put it there?
We just close it down here.
Massive losses with all
of the work we've done.
you know. getting power there.
getting the loos installed.
concrete floor. everything.
- building the shop itself.
- Yeah.
So why don't we go to
the council and say:
"How would you feel if we moved the
shop into the top end of the farm?"
So. I get the theory.
I get the logic. but...
I knew there'd be a "but".
There's no guarantee that they
will grant permission here.
So what we should do is...
Erm...
- Personally. I feel...
- You think fight it?
I don't think "fight" is
necessarily the right word.
It's the emotive word.
But actually what I think we
should do is put our views across
in a sensible.
logical. objective way.
- which has not been...
- Fight the fuckers.
Which has not been done.
Hammer them into the
ground like tent pegs.
I think some of their
points probably we do need
- to be more forceful than others.
- Yeah.
- And such as. you know...
- Lavatories.
Yeah.
They say we can't
have a lavatory.
So when you're a shop girl there and
you're not allowed to go to the...
- There won't be a lavatory.
- Or a shop-boy. You could be either.
It's more difficult. A
boy can go behind a bush.
If you need to go to the loo
you have to get in a
car. close the shop.
come all the way down. back
up. So there is a problem.
Anyway. I think
what we should do...
To not move it.
Not move it.
- Speak to a barrister.
- Not fight them.
And then we put in a robust.
- objective response.
- Robust.
Yes.
Well. I've been
watching Yellowstone.
When somebody displeases
them. they murder them.
take them across the state line
and throw them into a ravine.
I've been looking at that scene a lot.
Charlie retreated
to his own office
to start work on the appeal.
And while he did that.
Lisa and I went back to the
muddy business of pig farming.
Oh shit. Look at this.
We're stuck as I
don't know what now.
- We're stuck in the mud.
- Yeah. this ain't going.
They're coming
out to see the show.
Yes. they're
coming out to laugh at me.
Look. they are...
Look at them! They're
hilarious! Their little ears!
- "Look at our ears! Our ears!"
- They're gonna line up and laugh at us.
- They're growing so fast.
- They really are. yeah.
Right. I think we're gonna have to
accept this is going to stay here
until either we get
some frost or...
No. if I get the tractor. we
can pull it out with that.
As I returned with the Lambo.
Lisa and I got a bit of a surprise.
Hi. Lisa.
Hey. Oh. hey.
K! How were the hols?
Judith! You're back!
- Judith?
- Judith Chalmers.
Who's that?
- Holiday person. Doesn't matter.
- I've been on holiday once.
What do you think?
Not bad. right?
Not bad?
Yeah! Look.
Last time I see this field.
it was a lovely potato field.
I know. but now look at it.
It's a massive pig enterprise.
- I know. it's brilliant. innit?
- Firstly... Firstly hear me out.
Who the fuck done the fencing?
We did!
Who's "we"?
Lisa and me. In
a rainstorm. at night.
we got the whole fencing done.
- Look at it!
- What's the matter with it?
Well. firstly. you haven't even
got all the posts the same height.
But that
doesn't matter. Kaleb.
It does!
And there's the road!
Look! Again. I can't...
Don't be picky.
- What's wrong with the road?
- Everyone's gonna see it. It looks shit.
Oh. I see- -
Look! Look down that line.
Did you use a
string line or not?
- What?
- Did you use a string line?
We didn't really
have time for that.
We were really... We had to
do it. It was a rush job.
Anyway. we've done it.
Not one has escaped. We put
a sign on the road saying:
"Kaleb built these fences."
It's just all brilliant.
- So...
- The pigs look amazing. actually.
Let me explain
how it works. because...
- Piggy!
- I've been reading a book.
- We've got the weaners there.
- Yeah.
We've got the boar
and two sows in here.
But we started there
and then we put him in
there with three sows.
- Three sows? Hang on.
- So he's now done the lot.
Honestly. there's been
pig orgy going on.
- You put the boar in here.
- Yeah.
And then in a week's space you
put it in with the other lot?
Yeah.
What's wrong with that?
No. you're joking?
You're kidding?
Please. tell me you're lying?
No.
Have you
counted their nipples?
- No.
- A pig's got. like. 14 nipples.
Yeah? They have litters
of. like. 10 to 14.
But well. I've done it.
Yeah. but you space
it out a little bit.
You don't have 50
piglets at the same time.
You're gonna have 50 small little
piglets running around at the same time.
Honestly!
Fucking hell!
I'd be highly cautious about
doing anything around these banks.
Oh yeah!
Shit! I've never seen
incompetence like it.
Oh!
I am
flabbergasted.